const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the precursor of adenine monophosphate and guanine monophosphate ?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphoribosyl triphosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Orotate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Inosine monophosphate (IMP)","bool":true},{"option":"Glutamine","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Penile urethra is mainly formed from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Vesical part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Phallic part of urogenital sinus","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"An increase in which of the following leads to a subsequent decrease in the glomerular filtration rate?","answers":[{"option":"Peritubular capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular capillary hydrostatic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular capillary plasma oncotic pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Bowman's capsule plasma oncotic pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the correct order of the coverings of the kidneys from outwards to inwards?","answers":[{"option":"Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Paranephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal capsule - Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Paranephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Paranephric fat - Renal fascia - Perinephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Renal capsule - Paranephric fat - Perinephric fat - Renal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Perinephric fat - Renal fascia - Paranephric fat - Renal capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents to the outpatient clinic with generalized edema and periorbital edema. Blood tests and urine analysis reveal hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.7 g proteinuria. A renal biopsy is performed. Which of the following electron microscopic features is most likely to be present in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Crescent shaped glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Subepithelial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Subendothelial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Thick glomerular basement membrane with immune complex deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Effacement of foot process but no deposits","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"The kidneys are supplied by blood via renal arteries which arise directly from the abdominal aorta immediately distal to the origin of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Splenic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mesenteric artery","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"During a dissection class, second-year medical students discuss facts about the covering of the kidney. Which of the following statements is true?","answers":[{"option":"Perirenal fat lies external to the renal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia encloses the suprarenal gland","bool":true},{"option":"Pararenal fat continues with fascia iliaca","bool":false},{"option":"Perirenal fat continues with fascia transversalis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia directly covers the kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"The fusion of the lower pole of the kidney, causing the ureters to pass anterior to the isthmus of the kidney, is referred to as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rosette kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral double kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Aberrant kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Horseshoe kidney","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"The trigone of the urinary bladder develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Phallic part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Absorbed mesonephric duct","bool":true},{"option":"Vesical part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Paramesonephric duct","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male patient comes to the emergency department with a complaint of throbbing pain in the left loin radiating towards the ipsilateral groin. On radiological investigation, a ureteric calculus is seen. The calculus is likely to be lodged at which of the following sites?","answers":[{"option":"Uretero-pelvic junction","bool":true},{"option":"Trigone of the bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Renal medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic outlet","bool":false},{"option":"Renal papilla","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"The lymphatics from the middle part of the ureter drain into which of the following groups of lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Celiac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Para-aortic group","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following structures plays a key role in the countercurrent multiplication mechanism for concentrating urine in the nephron?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Vasa Recta","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"What type of transport mechanism exemplifies the sodium-potassium-chloride (Na-K-2Cl) transporter located on the apical membrane in the thick ascending limb of the Loop of Henle?","answers":[{"option":"Passive transport","bool":false},{"option":"Counter transport","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 65-year-old male is admitted to the hospital with symptoms of confusion, hyponatremia, and concentrated urine. The patient's medical history includes lung cancer and recent chemotherapy. Laboratory tests reveal low serum sodium levels and high urine osmolality. What is the most likely cause of the patient's symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Syndrome of inappropriate ADH secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperaldosteronism","bool":false},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes insipidus","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 55-year-old female undergoes a renal clearance test to assess the clearance of a substance that is freely filtered at the glomerulus and neither reabsorbed nor secreted by the renal tubules. The clearance value for this substance is found to be equal to the patient's glomerular filtration rate (GFR). Which of the following substances is most likely being measured in this test?","answers":[{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 55-year-old male is admitted to the hospital with complaints of excessive thirst and polyuria (excessive urine production). Laboratory tests reveal low urine osmolarity. Which of the following is the most likely explanation for the patient's symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced secretion of renin","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive release of aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Increased reabsorption of Na+ in the proximal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired release of antidiuretic hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Inadequate glomerular filtration rate","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following glucose transporters is primarily responsible for 90% of glucose reabsorption from the brush border epithelium of proximal convoluted tubules?","answers":[{"option":"SGLT1","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT2","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT3","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT1","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A research group is studying the functions of specific transporters in the renal tubules to assess their role in maintaining homeostasis. In this context, which of the following functions should be investigated to determine the primary role of pendrin in the renal tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Regulating blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitating glucose reabsorption","bool":false},{"option":"Maintaining acid-base balance","bool":true},{"option":"Reabsorbing sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Enhancing water reabsorption","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 42-year-old female is being treated for hypertension and is prescribed a diuretic that inhibits sodium reabsorption in the early distal convoluted tubule. Which type of diuretic is most likely being used?","answers":[{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Loop diuretic","bool":false},{"option":"Thiazide diuretic","bool":true},{"option":"Osmotic diuretic","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone antagonist","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which segment of the renal tubule is water impermeable, allowing solutes like sodium and chloride to passively diffuse into the medullary interstitial space?","answers":[{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Thin ascending limb loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Descending limb loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Thick ascending limb loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most abundant closed buffer in the proximal tubular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A patient is undergoing a renal function test to determine the clearance of substance X. After a urine collection period, it is found that the concentration of substance X in urine (U) is 200 mg/dL, the concentration of substance X in plasma (P) is 20 mg/dL, and the urine flow rate (V) is 1.2 mL/min. What would be the renal clearance of substance X?","answers":[{"option":"C= 12 mL/min","bool":true},{"option":"C= 2 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"C= 0.1 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"C= 1200 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"C= 200 mL/min","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Two samples of filtrate are taken from the beginning and end of the proximal tubules by a micropipette for comparison. Which one of the following substances would be present in large quantity at the end as compared to the beginning?","answers":[{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"In an experiment, 5 grams of substance A is found to be filtered at the glomeruli per day, while 7 grams of the same substance is excreted in urine per day. Which one of the following statements justifies the above condition?","answers":[{"option":"All of that substance is reabsorbed","bool":false},{"option":"Substance is both reabsorbed and secreted","bool":false},{"option":"Rate of filtration equals rate of excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Substance is synthesized in the tubular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Substance is secreted by the nephron","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which blood vessels surround the loops of Henle?","answers":[{"option":"Efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Interlobular arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa recta","bool":true},{"option":"Interlobar arteries","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Cytidine triphosphate (CTP) is produced by the amination of UTP (Uridine triphosphate) by which one of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"UTP transferase","bool":false},{"option":"CTP synthetase","bool":true},{"option":"Ribonucleotide reductase","bool":false},{"option":"CTP synthase","bool":false},{"option":"CTP kinase","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 3-month-old infant was brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of an eczematous rash along with vomiting. In addition, he had a musty and mousy odor in his urine. The infant had blond hair, blue eyes along with fair skin. Which of the following diseases is most likely to be linked in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylketonuria","bool":true},{"option":"Cystinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Maple syrup disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Glycinuria","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Many substances are cleared by the kidney. Under normal physiological conditions the clearance of which of the following substances is zero?","answers":[{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Phenolphthalein","bool":false},{"option":"PAH","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which one of the following actions is inhibited by parathyroid hormone in the renal tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphate secretion in proximal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium reabsorption in distal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate reabsorption in proximal tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium secretion in distal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium reabsorption in loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A healthy 25-year-old male participates in a marathon race on a hot and humid day and becomes dehydrated. In which of the following segments of his nephron, maximum water will be reabsorbed in the presence of high levels of antidiuretic hormone (ADH)?","answers":[{"option":"Descending limb of Loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting ducts","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"The arterial blood gas (ABG) analysis of a 44-year-old female with a history of severe diarrhea showed a pH of 7.25, PCO2= 24 mmHg, HCO3= 10mEq/L, and K+= 2.5mEq/l. Which one of the following conditions is the most appropriate diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Normal status","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"What is the net filtration pressure at the glomerulus if the glomerular hydrostatic pressure is 44 mmHg, Bowman's capsule hydrostatic pressure is 9mmHg, the osmotic pressure of plasma is 28mmHg, and the osmotic pressure of the tubular fluid is 0mmHg?","answers":[{"option":"14 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"11 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"7 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"18 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"21 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female with uncontrolled diabetes was found to have a plasma glucose level of 300 mg/dl with a normal glomerular filtration rate. Which one of the following values corresponds to the calculated filtered load of glucose in this case?","answers":[{"option":"250 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"575 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"450 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"150 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"375 mg/dl","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"In muscle tissue, creatine and phosphocreatine produce creatinine as a waste product excreted from the body. The creatinine clearance test is that it is the marker of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tubular function","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular function","bool":true},{"option":"Urolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Measurement of skeletal muscle mass","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder function","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"In tissues that do not carry out active de novo synthesis, how is an adequate supply of adenine nucleotides maintained?","answers":[{"option":"It requires ATP uptake from the blood","bool":false},{"option":"It is accomplished entirely by the action of adenylate kinase","bool":false},{"option":"It depends upon the action of nucleoside phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"It involves hypoxanthine salvage using HG-PRT","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs primarily by adenine salvage using A-PRT","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 55-year-old man presents with hypertension, puffiness of his face, and darkening of urine. Serum levels of blood urea nitrogen (BUN) are raised. Urinalysis reports numerous RBCs and occasional red cell casts. He was admitted for further investigations. Which of the following serum proteins will be found depleted in this patient suggesting an immune-complex mediated renal involvement?","answers":[{"option":"Complement C3","bool":true},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor (factor XII)","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloid","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy abruptly develops malaise, fever, nausea, oliguria, and hematuria (smoky or cola-colored urine) one to two weeks after recovery from a sore throat. The patient has red cell casts in the urine, mild proteinuria (< 1 gm/day), periorbital edema, and mild to moderate hypertension. Which of the following best describes this patient's medical condition?","answers":[{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Polycystic kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 7-year-old boy has been diagnosed with post-infectious glomerulonephritis resulting in nephritic syndrome. The child has hematuria as a part of this syndrome. Which of the following findings on urinalysis would suggest that RBCs in his urine are coming from the kidneys and not from lower down the urinary tract?","answers":[{"option":"White cell casts","bool":false},{"option":"Red cell casts","bool":true},{"option":"Urobilinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Blood clots","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages containing red cells","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"Muscle-invasive bladder cancers are associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Amplification of c-myc gene","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of TP53 & Rb tumor suppressor genes","bool":true},{"option":"Activations of TP53 & RB tumor suppressor genes","bool":false},{"option":"Translocation of TFE3 gene","bool":false},{"option":"Gene notations of MET proto-oncogene","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 42-year-old man has had recurrent episodes of urinary tract infections (UTIs) over the last six months. Urine culture has yielded the growth of Proteus mirabilis on three occasions. Which one of the following could be the most likely underlying cause?","answers":[{"option":"Reflux nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Enterovesical fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Schistosomiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal calculi","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A patient with severe recurrent gout, who had been taking high doses of analgesics, presented with malaise and nausea. Laboratory findings showed raised serum urea and creatinine levels. Which one of the following diseases is he suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Renal papillary necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hydronephrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular injury","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man had left flank pain. Ultrasonography showed bilaterally enlarged kidneys with multiple variable-size cysts in both the cortex and medulla. A few cysts in the liver were also seen. What is the most likely pattern of inheritance of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":true},{"option":"Cytogenetic disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal co-dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"An elderly patient with a history of heart disease has difficulty breathing and is diagnosed with acute pulmonary edema. Which of the following drugs is indicated as a drug of first choice to treat this problem?","answers":[{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorthalidone","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A patient was referred to your clinic by a physician with a note that the patient's chronic illness is not improving despite getting all treatment options for his illness. Evaluate the patient and share your expert opinion. What steps would you like to consider in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Ensure compliance of patient","bool":false},{"option":"Evaluate the risk factors and barriers of treatment adherence","bool":true},{"option":"Guide the caregiver for adherence","bool":false},{"option":"Address the issues of patient","bool":false},{"option":"Change in medicine/drug regime","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 34-year-old female presented to the outpatient department with decreased urination and pedal edema. On examination, there was a renal bruit on the right side. Her blood pressure was 160/100 mmHg. Her primary care physician prescribed her antihypertensive medication a week ago. Her investigations revealed a Hb of 12.1 gm/dl, urea 109 mg/dl, creatinine 4.2 mg/dl, Na⁺ 138 mEq/l, K⁺ 5.4 mEq/L. Which of the following antihypertensive must have been prescribed to her which resulted in increased serum creatinine level?","answers":[{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Thiazide diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"ACE inhibitors","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 26-year-old female presented to the outpatient department with loose watery stools for 2 days, occurring almost 10-15 episodes per day. It was not associated with fever or blood in stools. On examination, she was severely dehydrated and had decreased urinary output. Her investigations showed a Hb of 15.9 gm/dl, MCV 92, platelets 162 × 10⁹, urea 112 mg/dl, creatinine 4.2 mg/dl, Na⁺ 136 mEq/l, K⁺ 4.2 mEq/L, HCO₃⁻: 16 mEq/L. What should be the immediate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Adequate hydration","bool":true},{"option":"Oral-rehydration salt (ORS)","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Hemodialysis","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 68-year-old male presented with decreased urinary output and pedal edema for 6 months. He has been diabetic for 30 years and has recently started developing recurrent hypoglycemia. Which of the following tests is most pertinent for establishing chronic kidney disease?","answers":[{"option":"Urine DR for proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"eGFR","bool":true},{"option":"Electrolytes and arterial blood gases (ABGs)","bool":false},{"option":"Serum albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Urea and creatinine","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presents in the emergency department with upper abdominal pain for the last 2 days and gradual deterioration in consciousness over the last 6 hours. He has been previously well. On examination, his blood pressure in 100/70mmHg, pulse 130/minute, respiratory rate 30/min with rapid and deep breathing, and he was afebrile. Arterial blood gas shows pH 7.10, PCO₂ 20 mmHg, PO₂ 60 mmHg, HCO₃ 6 meq/L. What is the acid-base disorder in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"No acid-base disturbance","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male presents in the emergency department with sudden loss of consciousness after ingesting some unknown compound. He had been previously well. On examination, his blood pressure is 100/70mmHg, pulse 90/minute, respiratory rate 6/min, and he is afebrile. He is not following commands and does not open his eyes to pain even. Arterial blood gas shows a pH of 7.10, PCO₂ 80 mmHg, PO₂ 60 mmHg, HCO₃, 27 mEq/L. What is the acid-base disorder in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis with increase anion-gap","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male patient has presented with sudden-onset, severe watery diarrhea that has persisted for four days. He experiences approximately 15 episodes of diarrhea per day and also vomiting. There is no blood in the stool. Upon examination, he has marked dehydration, a temperature of 38.5 °C, and a rapid heart rate. Which of the following electrolyte imbalances is he at risk of developing?","answers":[{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 54-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with a history of recurrent headaches due to sinusitis, for which he took non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) regularly. His initial investigations showed a Hb of 11.2 gm/dl, a total leukocyte count (TLC) of 4.8 ×10 ³, 58% neutrophils, 28% lymphocytes, 12% eosinophils, and 2% monocytes. Urea is 98 mg/dl and creatinine is 2.1 gm/dl. Urine analysis is positive for protein. What is the most likely reason for his deranged laboratory tests?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial nephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"End-stage renal disease","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr